<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>publication | Nan Laboratory</title>
    <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/tag/publication/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://nanrock008.github.io/tag/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>publication</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>NanLab 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://nanrock008.github.io/images/logo_hudafa2c7080e4ffebc6f3bf0b6b58f48b_217893_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>publication</title>
      <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/tag/publication/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our work on anisotropic magnon spin transport was published in Nano Letters.</title>
      <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/post/mafo1_paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanrock008.github.io/post/mafo1_paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.nanolett.1c04332&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Anisotropic magnon spin transport in ultrathin spinel ferrite thin films-evidence for anisotropy in exchange stiffness&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is now out at Nano Letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magnon-mediated spin flow in magnetically ordered insulators enables long-distance spin-based information transport with low dissipation. In the materials studied to date, no anisotropy has been observed in the magnon propagation length as a function of propagation direction. Here, we report measurements of magnon spin transport in a spinel ferrite, magnesium aluminum ferrite MgAl0.5Fe1.5O4 (MAFO), which has a substantial in-plane 4-fold magnetic anisotropy. We observe spin diffusion lengths &amp;gt; 0.8 μm at room temperature in 6 nm films, with spin diffusion lengths 30% longer along the easy axes compared to the hard axes. The sign of this difference is opposite to the effects just of anisotropy in the magnetic energy for a uniform magnetic state. We suggest instead that accounting for anisotropy in exchange stiffness is necessary to explain these results. These findings provide an approach for controlling magnon transport via strain, which opens new opportunities for designing magnonic devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruofan Li, Peng Li, Di Yi, Lauren J. Riddiford, Yahong Chai, Yuri Suzuki, Daniel C. Ralph, and Tianxiang Nan
, &lt;em&gt;Nano Letters&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;, 1167-1173 (2022)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our work on voltage control of spin dynamics was published in Science Advances.</title>
      <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/post/ferh_paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 19:57:38 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanrock008.github.io/post/ferh_paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://advances.sciencemag.org/content/6/40/eabd2613&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Electric-field control of spin dynamics during magnetic phase transitions&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is now out at Science Advances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this work, we propose an approach to manipulate the damping by using the large damping enhancement induced by the two-magnon scattering and a nonlocal spin relaxation process in which spin currents are resonantly transported from antiferromagnetic domains to ferromagnetic matrix in a mixed-phased metallic alloy FeRh. This damping enhancement in FeRh is sensitive to its fraction of antiferromagnetic and ferromagnetic phases, which can be dynamically tuned by electric fields through a strain-mediated magnetoelectric coupling. In a heterostructure of FeRh and piezoelectric PMN-PT, we demonstrated a more than 120% modulation of the effective damping by electric fields during the antiferromagnetic-to-ferromagnetic phase transition. Our results demonstrate an efficient approach to controlling the magnetization dynamics, thus enabling low-power tunable electronics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tianxiang Nan, Yeonbae Lee, Shihao Zhuang, Zhongqiang Hu, James D. Clarkson, Xinjun Wang, Changhyun Ko, HwanSung Choe, Zuhuang Chen, David Budil, Junqiao Wu, Sayeef Salahuddin, Jiamian Hu, Ramamoorthy Ramesh, Nian Sun, &lt;em&gt;Science Advances&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt;, eabd2613 (2020)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our work on antiferromagentic spintronics was published in Nature Communications.</title>
      <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/post/mgn_nc-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 12:36:38 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanrock008.github.io/post/mgn_nc-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-17999-4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Controlling spin current polarization through non-collinear antiferromagnetism&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is now out at Nature Communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this work, we show control of the spin polarization direction by using a non-collinear antiferromagnet Mn3GaN, in which the triangular spin structure creates a low magnetic symmetry while maintaining a high crystalline symmetry. We demonstrate that epitaxial Mn3GaN/permalloy heterostructures can generate unconventional spin-orbit torques at room temperature corresponding to out-of-plane and Dresselhaus-like spin polarizations which are forbidden in any sample with two-fold rotational symmetry. Our results demonstrate an approach based on spin-structure design for controlling spin-orbit torque, enabling high-efficient antiferromagnetic spintronics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T. Nan, C. X. Quintela, J. Irwin, &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt;, 4671 (2020)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
