<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spin Hall effect | Nan Laboratory</title>
    <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/tag/spin-hall-effect/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://nanrock008.github.io/tag/spin-hall-effect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Spin Hall effect</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>NanLab 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://nanrock008.github.io/images/logo_hudafa2c7080e4ffebc6f3bf0b6b58f48b_217893_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Spin Hall effect</title>
      <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/tag/spin-hall-effect/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient spin-to-charge conversion for spintronics</title>
      <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/project/sio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanrock008.github.io/project/sio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent exciting discoveries in the field of spintronics include the creating or detecting of spin currents in non-magnetic materials or interfaces with strong spin-orbit coupling, which originates from bulk spin-Hall or interfacial Rashba effects. Importantly, the spin-orbit interaction induced spin polarized currents can interact with magnetic moment and exert torque on the adjacent magnetic materials. Such torque, also known as spin-orbit torque, can efficiently switch the magnetization, and provide means of controlling topological solitons in chiral spin textures (i.e. skyrmions). Materials with high-efficient intrinsic spin-charge conversion is the key to enable those interesting applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strongly correlated materials, which harbor quantum many-body system, can be a fertile playground for both fundamental understanding of spin-orbit effects, since the interplay between electron correlation and spin-orbit interaction can give rise to non-trivial electronic band topologies and nonzero Berry curvature. However, such materials have not been fully exploited in the fundamental studies or applications of spintronics so far. We have shown that a perovskite correlated semimetal SrIrO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; can indeed generate pure spin current via the spin-Hall effect at room temperature more efficiently than that reported for elemental heavy metals. The efficiency can also be strongly modified by epitaxially tailoring the SrIrO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; lattice symmetry, thus suggesting a path toward engineering efficient room-temperature spintronics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-publications&#34;&gt;Related publications:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pnas.org/content/116/33/16186&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Anisotropic spin-orbit torque generation in epitaxial SrIrO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; by symmetry design, &lt;em&gt;PNAS&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;116&lt;/strong&gt;, 16186-16191, (2019)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/adfm.201806371&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;A strain-mediated magnetoelectric-spin-torque hybrid structure, &lt;em&gt;Advanced Functional Materials&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;29&lt;/strong&gt;, 1806371, (2019)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.aps.org/prb/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevB.101.104405&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Spontaneous Hall Effect enhanced by local Ir moments in epitaxial Pr&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Ir&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; thin films, &lt;em&gt;Physical Review B&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;101&lt;/strong&gt;, 104405 , (2020)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Strain-Mediated Magnetoelectric-Spin-Torque Hybrid Structure</title>
      <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/publication/nan-2019-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanrock008.github.io/publication/nan-2019-c/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anisotropic spin-orbit torque generation in epitaxial SrIrO3 by symmetry design</title>
      <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/publication/nan-2019-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanrock008.github.io/publication/nan-2019-b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
