<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Nan Laboratory</title>
    <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://nanrock008.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>NanLab 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://nanrock008.github.io/images/logo_hudafa2c7080e4ffebc6f3bf0b6b58f48b_217893_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic antennas</title>
      <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/project/antenna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanrock008.github.io/project/antenna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is predicted that over 75 billion of IoT devices will be ready for connection by 2025, via antennas. There are clearly big opportunities for miniaturized antennas. However, the antenna miniaturization has been an open challenge for centuries, until recently. We have created small antennas that have size &lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt; times smaller than the state-of-the-art antennas through the innovation in their radiation and transmission mechanisms. We proposed a new acoustically actuated antenna concept: the use of acoustic waves to drive the oscillation of magnetic moment which radiates electromagnetic waves. We constructed and integrated our antennas by the combination of microelectromechanical system (MEMS) and the magnetoelectric thin film materials onto silicon wafers. Such game-changing antennas no longer resonate with electromagnetic waves but radiate electromagnetic waves by the actuation of acoustic waves. Because acoustic waves have much smaller wavelength (as the acoustic wave velocity is much smaller than that of the light wave), we created an acoustic antenna, which operates at 2.5 GHz, miniaturizes the current antenna size over two orders of magnitudes. Our work would bring revolutionary advancement to IoTs, wireless communications, wearable and implantable bio-sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;selected-news-report&#34;&gt;Selected News report:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2017/08/mini-antennas-could-power-brain-computer-interfaces-medical-devices&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mini-antennas could power brain-computer interfaces, medical devices&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; doi:10.1126/science.aap7452&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/news/ultra-small-antennas-point-way-to-miniature-brain-implants-1.22507&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ultra-small antennas point way to miniature brain implants&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; doi:10.1038/nature.2017.22507&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://spectrum.ieee.org/tech-talk/telecom/wireless/tiny-membranebased-antennas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tiny Membrane-Based Antennas&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;IEEE spectrum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-publication&#34;&gt;Related publication:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-017-00343-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Acoustically actuated ultra-compact NEMS magnetoelectric antennas&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;, 296, (2017)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient spin-to-charge conversion for spintronics</title>
      <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/project/sio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanrock008.github.io/project/sio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent exciting discoveries in the field of spintronics include the creating or detecting of spin currents in non-magnetic materials or interfaces with strong spin-orbit coupling, which originates from bulk spin-Hall or interfacial Rashba effects. Importantly, the spin-orbit interaction induced spin polarized currents can interact with magnetic moment and exert torque on the adjacent magnetic materials. Such torque, also known as spin-orbit torque, can efficiently switch the magnetization, and provide means of controlling topological solitons in chiral spin textures (i.e. skyrmions). Materials with high-efficient intrinsic spin-charge conversion is the key to enable those interesting applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strongly correlated materials, which harbor quantum many-body system, can be a fertile playground for both fundamental understanding of spin-orbit effects, since the interplay between electron correlation and spin-orbit interaction can give rise to non-trivial electronic band topologies and nonzero Berry curvature. However, such materials have not been fully exploited in the fundamental studies or applications of spintronics so far. We have shown that a perovskite correlated semimetal SrIrO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; can indeed generate pure spin current via the spin-Hall effect at room temperature more efficiently than that reported for elemental heavy metals. The efficiency can also be strongly modified by epitaxially tailoring the SrIrO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; lattice symmetry, thus suggesting a path toward engineering efficient room-temperature spintronics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-publications&#34;&gt;Related publications:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pnas.org/content/116/33/16186&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Anisotropic spin-orbit torque generation in epitaxial SrIrO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; by symmetry design, &lt;em&gt;PNAS&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;116&lt;/strong&gt;, 16186-16191, (2019)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/adfm.201806371&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;A strain-mediated magnetoelectric-spin-torque hybrid structure, &lt;em&gt;Advanced Functional Materials&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;29&lt;/strong&gt;, 1806371, (2019)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.aps.org/prb/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevB.101.104405&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Spontaneous Hall Effect enhanced by local Ir moments in epitaxial Pr&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Ir&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; thin films, &lt;em&gt;Physical Review B&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;101&lt;/strong&gt;, 104405 , (2020)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MEMS magnetic sensors</title>
      <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/project/sensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanrock008.github.io/project/sensor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Compact magnetometers show potential to detect neuronal activity that could advance the brain-machine interface technology. We have developed a new class of miniaturized magnetometers by using the MEMS nano-plate resonators loaded with magnetic thin films. By the detection of frequency shifts in these devices, we were able to approach a magnetic field detection limit of a few hundreds pico-Tesla. We have also interfaced the MEMS magnetometer with a low power CMOS oscillator for integrated MEMS-CMOS systems with the direct frequency readout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-publications&#34;&gt;Related publications:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/srep01985&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Self-biased 215MHz magnetoelectric NEMS resonator for ultra-sensitive DC magnetic field detection, &lt;em&gt;Scientific reports&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;, 1985, (2013)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6819410&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;High Resolution Magnetometer Based on a High Frequency Magnetoelectric MEMS-CMOS Oscillator, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Microelectromechanical Systems&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt;, 134, (2015)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/adma.201602910&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Highly sensitive flexible magnetic sensor based on anisotropic magnetoresistance effect, &lt;em&gt;Advanced Materials&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;28&lt;/strong&gt;, 9370, (2016)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/1.4979694&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ultra-sensitive NEMS magnetoelectric sensor for picotesla DC magnetic field detection, &lt;em&gt;Applied Physics Letters&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;110&lt;/strong&gt;, 143510 , (2017)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unconventional spin-orbit torques in non-collinear antiferromagnets</title>
      <link>https://nanrock008.github.io/project/mgn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nanrock008.github.io/project/mgn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Current-induced spin-orbit torque enables highly efficient manipulation of magnetization for spintronic applications. To efficiently and deterministically drive, for example, perpendicularly-magnetized devices that are preferred for high-density memories, an out-of-plane anti-damping torque is required. However, symmetry conditions generally restrict anti-damping torque to lie in the sample plane. We have demonstrated a strategy to achieve unconventional spin-orbit torques, based on long-range non-collinear magnetic order within the bulk of the spin-source layer. These spin torques correspond to out-of-plane and Dresselhaus-like spin polarizations which are forbidden in any sample with two-fold rotational symmetry. This approach could enable high efficient manipulation of magnetization for antiferromagnetic spintronics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-publications&#34;&gt;Related publications:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-17999-4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Controlling spin current polarization through non-collinear antiferromagnetism, &lt;em&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt;, 4671 (2020)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://advances.sciencemag.org/content/6/30/eaba4017&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Epitaxial antiperovskite/perovskite heterostructures for materials design, &lt;em&gt;Science Advances&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt;, eaba4017 (2020)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
